Cousins. Outlaws. Thrillbillies.
The Dukes of Hazzard is a comedy, adventure, action
film directed by Jay Chandrasekhar.
Cousins, Bo and Luke Duke, with the help of their eye-catching cousin, Daisy and moonshine-running Uncle Jesse, try
and save the family farm from being destroyed by Hazzard County's corrupt commissioner, Boss Hogg.
Their efforts constantly find the 'Duke Boys' eluding authorities in 'The General Lee', their 1969 orange Dodge Charger
that keeps them one step ahead of the dimwitted antics of the small southern town's Sheriff, Roscoe P.
Luke Duke, played by Johnny Knoxville.
Bo Duke, played by Seann William Scott.
Daisy Duke, played by Jessica Simpson.
Uncle Jesse Duke, played by Willie Nelson.
Jefferson Davis 'Boss' Hogg, played by Burt Reynolds.
Sheriff Rosco P. Coltrane, played by M.C. Gainey.
The Dukes of Hazzard is a 2005 American action comedy film loosely
based on the television series of the same name.
The film is the third installment of The Dukes of Hazzard film series.
It was directed by Jay Chandrasekhar and stars Johnny Knoxville, Seann William Scott, Jessica Simpson in
her feature film debut, Burt Reynolds, Joe Don Baker, Lynda Carter, and Willie Nelson.
As in the television series, the film depicts the adventures of cousins Bo, Luke, and Daisy, and their
Uncle Jesse, as they outfox crooked Hazzard County Commissioner Boss Hogg and Sheriff Rosco P.
The film was released on August 5, 2005, by Warner Bros.
While financially successful with an opening debut of $30 million and a worldwide gross of
$109.8 million, the film met with generally negative reviews from critics.
The film was followed by a standalone prequel titled The
Dukes of Hazzard: The Beginning (2007).
The film explores themes of farm, sheriff, bikini, redneck, moonshine.
The tone is lighthearted.